"伊波拉浩劫" 前情提要
Previously on The Hot Zone...
我们正在处理的事情可能比以往遇到的任何情况都要糟糕
What we're dealing with could be worse than anything we've ever seen.
我们这儿有一整支团队
We do have a team here.
我的团队
My team.
我的意思是 我刚刚亲自甄选出最好的队员
I mean, I just finished handpicking the best crew to go in
我还没向他们作情况简报
and I haven't even briefed them yet.
伊波拉-扎伊尔毒株被定义为四级生化危害病原体的原因是
The reason Ebola Zaire is classified as a BL4 agent is there's no vaccine.
没有疫苗 无法治愈
No treatment.
我们面对的敌人有能力摧毁一座城市
We are facing an enemy that can devastate a city.
而你们就是矗立在这个敌人和门外平民之间的一道屏障
And you're what's standing between it and the civilians outside those doors.
南希根本就不应该让卡特加入进来
Nancy should never have brought Carter in.
如果你让我代替南希来负责
If you put me in charge instead of Nancy...
别误会我 杰瑞
Don't get me wrong, Jerry.
南希是这儿最优秀的人之一
Nancy's one of the best we've ever had come through here.
但她这次做错了决定
But she hitched herself to the wrong horse on this one.
我跟你说过 我有多么不希望你进去
I told you how much I didn't want you going in there.
我了解那些病原体 杰瑞
I know these pathogens, Jerry!
也许比任何人都了解
Probably more than anybody else.
我接受了那么多年的培训就是为了这一天
This is the day I've been trained for!
我才是那个可以牺牲的
I'm the one who's expendable.
我跟杰瑞一起去
I'm going in with Jerry.
里面有事情等着做 无关个人
Job's got to get done. It's not personal.
去他妈的无关个人
Oh, like hell it isn't.
总得有人去抓那个怪物
Somebody's going to get the monster.
如果感觉心跳开始加速就开始呼吸
If you find your heart start to race, just breathe it through.
卡特 开灯 嘿 没关系
Carter light. It's okay, it's okay.
重新找一个
Find a new one.
我们得从所有工人以及
We need to draw blood from all the workers
他们身体接触过的所有人身上抽血 马上
and whoever they were in physical contact with now.
我可以今晚检测他们
I can have them tested tonight.
我可以派人守住大楼入口 确保没人能进去
I can station someone outside the building, but we need to be careful.
媒体到处在打听
The press sniffing around,
他们会开始问问题
they're going to start asking questions.
你们将要与一种病毒战斗
You're going into combat against a virus for whom
幸存是最重要的
survival is all that matters.
你们也要这样 我们就都能回家
You guys think the same way and we all come home.
好的 都听好了
All right, listen up.
这个地方已经废弃了34个小时
This location's been abandoned for 34 hours.
那里的动物都饿得慌
Animals in there are hungry.
预计会有激烈的反应
Expect a violent reaction.
小动物们不喜欢穿制服的人
Little guys don't like the suits.
但请不要忘记 它们可不是可憎的敌人
And let's not forget, these are not hostile enemies.
它们只是被动卷入了旋涡的灵长类动物
Just primates who got involved in something they did not ask for.
它们和我们的目标一样...
They have the same goal we do...
生存
To survive.
伊波拉病毒也是如此
Just like Ebola.
只不过 它比我们更聪明 更擅长生存
Except it's smarter and better at it than we are.
预计什么时候到
What's our ETA?
-大概一个小时  -很好
-About an hour. -Good.
我们要在没人注意到我们之前完成任务
We need to get in and get out before anyone knows we're there.
陆军传染病医学研究院指挥中心
USAMRIID command.
喂 我是狄克逊...告诉车队
Hey, it's Dixon... get word to the convoy.
中止计划 中止计划 有人在窥视我们
Abort, a-abort. Someone's snooping around.
高速公路再过两个街区就到了
Highway's just two blocks up.
91探戈 中止计划
91-Tango Abort.
接收到狄克逊的消息
Got word from Dixon.
有人在该区域内
Someone is on the premises.
我是贾克斯上校
This is Colonel Jaax.
他为什么不直接用无线电通知我们
Why didn't he radio us directly?
雷斯顿可能超出信号范围了 长官
It's possible Reston is out of range, sir.
我现在和信号小组确认下
Checking with ASE Ops now.
这事不能等
This isn't something we wait on.
已经拖了太久了
It's been stalled too long already.
我们得到的明确指示是避免暴露
Express orders to avoid exposure.
不要引起公众恐慌
Not stir up any public panic.
南希能分得清轻重缓急...
Nancy understands the urgency...
我才是这次行动的指挥官
I am in command of this mission.
你要对南希负责 要尊重这一点
You're going to do right by Nancy and honor that.
她为你担保 你做的一切都算在她头上
She vouched for you. Every move you make is on her.
-上校 是否中止计划  -不 等一下
-Colonel, do we abort? -No, not yet.
狄克逊 状况如何
Dixon, what's your status?
我是邮报的
I'm from the Post.
你知道这里爆发了什么吗
Do you know anything about an outbreak here?
我保证不会泄露我的线人...
I promise I won't reveal my sources...
不知道 我只是个夜猫子
Uh, no, I-I'm just the night guy.
出来走走看看
Just keep an eye on the place.
真的吗
Really.
你确定什么都没有看见吗
You sure you haven't seen anything?
一点奇怪的都没有
Nothing strange at all?
是的 很安静 和平常一样
No, all quiet. As usual.
你非常快地从车里跳出来 跑到这里来
Hey, you jumped out of your car pretty quickly, bolted over here.
狄克逊
Dixon.
你在和谁通电话
Who you on the phone with?
我女朋友
My girlfriend.
狄克逊
Dixon.
她总是想查我的岗...
She always wants me to check in...
她要是在电话这头听到另一个女人的声音会杀了我的
She'd kill me if she heard another woman's voice on the end of this line.
状态更新
Status update.
他还没回应 长官 等一下
He's not responding sir, standby.
你要是看见了什么 打给我
If you see anything, call me.
别傻站着
Don't freeze out here.
狄克逊 请回复 发生什么了
Dixon, respond. What the hell is going on?
等一下
Just, just hang on a second.
上校 中止计划吗
Colonel, do we abort?
通过上匝道 等下一个
Pass this on-ramp. Wait for the next.
去下一个
Go to the next one.
必须尽快 不然就晚了
This has to happen, sooner rather than later.
越快大家就越安全
Sooner is safer for everyone.
我说了等一下
I say we wait.
等一下
Hold on.
好了 她走了
We're good, she's leaving.
可以继续了 长官
All clear to proceed, sir.
记者已经离开了
Reporter has left the premises.
收到
Roger that.
博萨是对的
Bosa was right.
隔离是唯一能阻止病毒传播的方法
Isolation is the only thing that stops this thing spreading.
这病毒到底是从哪里冒出来的
How does a virus like this just come out of nowhere?
不是无中生有
It wasn't nowhere.
有些病毒在猪 蝙蝠 猴子身上有上千年了
There's been viruses in pigs, bats, monkeys, for thousands of years.
但是 当你拆了它们的家 它们就会相继死去
But when you cut down their homes and they die off,
怪物总要找个地方躲起来
the monsters got to hide somewhere.
怪物
Monster?
你见过什么能把身体弄成这样的吗
You ever seen anything destroy a body like this?
真是个完美的杀手
It's the perfect killer.
但它的"阿基里斯之踵"[致命弱点]可能是 它在人身上烧得太快
But its Achilles' heel may be it burns through people so fast
也就害死了自己
it snuffs itself out.
如果这病毒能在攻击人体之前
If this thing ever evolves to live in a human longer
进化到能在人体内存活更长时间
before it attacks the body,
那它的传播速度我们就完全跟不上了
it could spread faster than we could ever keep up with.
厄普斯特德 请到2号麻醉室
Upstead. Your anesthesiology code 2.
Upstead again anesthesiology code 2.
好了 把袖子卷上去
Okay. Roll up your sleeves.
我的丈夫会死吗
Is my husband going to die?
多曼斯基夫人...
Mrs. Domanski...
因为我听到出事了 我有三个孩子...
'Cause I've been hearing things and I have three kids...
布鲁斯和我经历过一些曲折 但我...
and Bruce and I have had our ups and downs but I...
我没法想象没有他 我该怎么熬过这一切…
I can't imagine going through all of this without him...
你孩子都几岁了
How old are your kids?
17岁 14岁 还有个9岁
They're, uh, 17, 14 and nine.
他们一定吓坏了...
They must be scared...
你陪着他们 我们都是为你丈夫而来的
Just be there for them and know that we're here for your husband.
他...他很稳定 没有发烧
He...he's steady. He hasn't spiked a fever.
失陪一下
Would you excuse me?
护士 能把那个给你吗
Nurse, could I give you that?
你归一下档吧 谢谢
Could you file that? Thank you.
我们得扩大扫除规模
We need to do a wider sweep.
在我们把工人带到这里之前
There's no telling how many people
还不知道他们接触了多少人
the workers had contact with before we got them here.
在扩大范围之前 我们得先看看是否有人感染
We need to see if any are even infected before we go wider.
另外 我们还要注意时间
Besides, we have a ticking clock on
还能要求这些人呆多久
how long we can even ask these people to stay.
有多少人出现症状了
How many have shown symptoms?
没人
None.
零症状
Zero symptoms.
继续测试吧 如果你想要见识疫情爆发
Run your tests, but if you're looking for an outbreak,
这里可见不到
you're not gonna find it here.
你在开玩笑吧
You got to be kidding me.
不是应该有人关闭游乐场吗
Wasn't someone supposed to close the playground?
现在来不及了
It's too late now.
长官 我是狄克逊中尉 他们让我守着前面
Sir! Lieutenant Dixon, sir. They had me at the front.
感谢你的盯梢 狄克逊
Thanks for keeping an eye out, Dixon.
我知道我没有参加完整的简报
I know I haven't had the full briefing,
但我以前穿过防护服
but I've had some experience in Racals.
我真的很想和大家一起进去
I really want to get in there with my team.
理解 但整个团队必须得协同工作
Understood. But the whole team's gotta work as a unit.
所有人都分配好任务了
Everyone's assigned already.
我们这次确实需要你看着那边
We do need you on the other side this time.
啊... 好的 长官
Ah man... Uh, yes, sir.
我们抓紧
Let's step it up.
我们需要把这些送到第四级
We need to take these into BL4.
那些是从医院来的吗
Are those from the hospital?
是的... 我们要测的血样
Yeah... blood samples we need to test.
所有接触人员和直系亲属
All contacts and immediate family members.
你们上次睡觉是什么时候
When was the last time you two slept?
我们俩轮班
Uh, we've been taking shifts.
问题是 办公椅不是很舒服
Problem is, the office chairs aren't really that comfy.
很难让大脑不去高速运转
It's hard to keep the mind from racing.
-还在担心吗  -多亏了工作
-And the anxiety? -Well, work helps.
问题是 我们停滞不前
Problem is, we're at a standstill.
雷斯顿那边什么都没送来
There's nothing in from Reston.
-还没东西送来吗  -有点延误了
-No deliveries yet? -Some kind of delay.
我不知道 他们甚至还没有进入大楼
I don't know, they haven't even entered the building.
我们必须得进去
We've got to get in there.
我们得知道这件事到底进展如何了
We need to know what's going on with this thing.
症状...
Something's off...
有些不对劲
the symptoms.
你们今天测试自己了吗
Have you tested yourselves today?
是啊 我们本来准备要测的 但...
I mean, yeah, we were going to but...
我们收到了铺天盖地的动物样本
It's like, we got thousands of animal samples incoming,
加上你带进来的血样...
plus all this blood that you're bringing in...
我们觉得应该没时间检测自己了
We didn't think there was going to be time.
是啊 但你得抽出时间
Yeah, well, you need to make the time.
听着 我知道这很可怕 但在我们进去之前你得先测
Look, I know this is scary but you need to do it before we go in there.
是啊
Yeah.
我去穿衣服
I'm going to suit up.
你觉得我们中有多少人被感染了
How many of us do you think have it?
我猜很快就知道了
Guess we'll know soon.
你爸爸担心过会发生这样的事吗
Your dad ever worry something like this would happen?
不 他只是喜欢照顾动物
Naw, he just liked taking care of the animals.
他说如果你找的话 会发现每一种都有有趣的怪癖
Said each one had a funny quirk if you looked for it.
谢了...
Thanks...
好了 伙计们 听好了
All right, guys, listen up.
这里是我们的突破口
This will be our sally port here.
完成了自己的消毒任务就来这儿
You come through here once you've deconned out.
我们将用胶带封住走廊的一部分 那儿就是灰色地带
We'll tape off a portion of the hallway for our grey zone.
是我们和外部的缓冲区
Our buffer to the outside world.
媒体在找我们 周围还有住户...
We're on the radar of the press and we got neighbors...
很多人盯着我们 不要穿着防护服走出这个机构
lot of eyes on us, so no one comes out of this facility in a suit.
里面的暖气仍是失灵状态
Inside, heating is still malfunctioning.
估计还有电力问题 所以...
Expecting issues with the electrical, so...
我们用手电筒
We'll go by flashlight.
房顶的灯不能用 所以会一路放置提灯
Can't use headlamps with the hoods, so we'll drop lanterns along the way,
每个房间两个
two in every room.
第一队打镇定剂 每个房间一个
The first team will be sedation, stationed one in every cell
直到动物全被清走
until each animal has been removed.
下一步 我们在这儿设置解剖小组
Next, we'll set up the dissection team here.
卡特会监管这个房间
Carter will supervise this room.
它们的速度会很快
They're coming fast.
一共500只 但你只需要专注于你面前的那只
500 by the end, but you just concentrate on the one in front of you.
采完血样后
After we take blood samples,
每只动物都会被送去安乐死
each animal will be brought to the euthanization station.
它们沉睡后 我们采组织样本
After they're put to sleep, we take tissue samples.
会有很多的血
There'll be a a lot of blood.
感染的血液
Infected blood.
如果你的防护服沾上了
If you get any on your suit,
停止你的工作 用消毒水它擦掉
stop what you're doing, and wipe it off with bleach.
这个病毒不像艾滋
The virus isn't like HIV.
一旦它进入空气 它可以活跃好几天
Once it hits the air, it can stay active for days.
我们现在就穿上防护服进去
We'll suit up to go into the building now.
在封锁灰色地带之前 整个地方可能都很热
The whole place might be hot until we can secure this grey zone.
无论你有什么原因要出去 我们都会让你出去的
If you need to get out for any reason, we'll get you out.
有疑问吗
Any questions?
确保胶带粘紧了
Make sure the tape is on tight.
封住每道缝隙
Cover very seal.
好了
Okay.
我们现在离开突破口 进入灰色地带
We're now leaving the Sally Port, and entering the Grey Zone.
14-1-4 让他们和我保持联系
14-1-4. Keep me at them.
这里是缓冲带 所有病毒一律不准进入这里
This is the buffer. Nothing hot comes in here.
我们还要消毒
We'll need to sterilize as well.
把消毒设备放在这里
We'll set up Decon through here.
好了 重点来了
All right, heads up.
这扇门后面就是最致命病毒隔离区
Beyond this door is the Hot Zone.
一旦进入这个区域 你的衣物就会被污染
Once you pass into the Hot Zone, your suits will be contaminated.
出来以后 请把衣物装进袋子 然后烧毁
When you're heading out, after Decon, bag them and burn them.
懂了吗
Okay?
把设备搬进来 我们要封上这扇门
Get the equipment in. We need to sheet this doorway.
是 长官
Yes, sir!
测试下空气开关
Trying the breaker.
不好 搞坏了
Nope. We blew it out.
我们只有用应急灯了
All we have are the emergency lights.
好 把灯装好 再把冷却机卸下来
Okay, let's get some lights set up and start unloading those coolers.
收到 是2-20型的
Roger that. That's a 2-20.
笼子有空的吗
Are some of these empty?
你没事 你没事
You're okay. You're okay.
哦 该死
Oh, hell no.
是猴子把这个扔到你身上的吗
Did one of them throw that at you?
反正我自己没扔
Well, I didn't throw it at myself.
它们用尽了方法来表达恐惧
They're using whatever means they have to express distress.
每一个污点都布满了病毒
Every smear is hot as can be.
谁都不准碰 把你的衣服消一下毒
No one touch it. And bleach that off your suit.
我身上到处都是病毒 千万不要碰我
I'm going go with everything is hot and don't touch anything.
我们反应越大 它们越会不依不饶
The more we react, the more they'll continue.
所以 保持冷静
So, stay calm.
好了 各位
All right, guys.
去拿镇静剂
Go get the sedation equipment.
这里的很多动物都表现得很暴力
Lot of these animals are exhibiting violent behavior.
对环境的变化异常敏感
Acute awareness of their surroundings.
其中一些并没有感染病毒
They're healthy, some of them.
但如果你想拯救任何一只 请打消这个念头
If you were thinking of saving any of these, forget it.
他们并不是人类 他们只是猴子
These aren't humans. They're monkeys.
我的工作是对人类和猴子一视同仁
My job is to not see the difference.
听着 你来自一个道德高尚的组织
Look, you're coming from a good place.
但我们根本没有时间
But we don't have the time to differentiate
去分辨哪些猴子感染了 哪些没有
between those infected and those who aren't...
任何一只都有可能已经被感染了
Everyone of one of them could have it.
找到一个
I've got one.
确定吗
You sure?
我也不喜欢我的显微镜下看到的东西
I don't like what I'm seeing over here either.
两个新增病例
Two new cases.
上帝啊 我们应该警告雷斯顿
Christ. We've got to alert Reston.
我们要给其他人都做测试
We should test the rest.
看看我们总共感染了多少例
See how many infections we have in total.
我去给医院打电话
I got to call the hospital.
我是贾克斯 给我接罗德斯
This is Jaax, get me Rhodes.
西护士站 请致电观察室
Nurses station west, please call OCU.
喂
Hello.
好 不 不 好了
Okay. No, no. Okay.
我们必须继续做测试
We have to go down tests.
不 你们等在这里
No, no. Just wait here.
他们在那里堆木棍
They're laying sticks down.
又有两个家庭感染了病毒
There's two more families infected.
大家都在躲着我们 就像躲那家人一样
We're being shunned, just like the family.
嘿 我们需要抹布
Hey, we need those rags!
时间到了 孩子要生了
It's time. The baby's coming.
你能来帮忙吗
You going to lend a hand?
病毒就是希望你现在去插手
That's exactly what it wants you to do.
让自己暴露 靠近它们
Expose yourself, get close.
那女人和孩子已经没救了
The woman and baby are lost.
他们都没救了
They're all lost.
告诉她 她必须试着把呼吸放缓
Tell her she has to try and slow her breathing down.
叫她深呼吸
Tell her to take deep breathes.
好了 她开始大出血了
All right, she's hemorrhaging.
她要生了 孩子要出来了
She's crowning. It's time.
叫她用力推 你要用力推啊 懂吗
Tell her she has to push. You have to push. Okay?
对了 就这样
That's it! That's it!
深呼吸 用力推
Deep breathes and push hard!
你可以的
You can do it!
加油 加油 再用力推一下
Come on! Come on! One big push.
就这样 很好 非常棒
That's it. That's good, that's good.
加油 很好 呼吸 呼吸
Come on. That's good, breathe. Breathe.
继续呼吸
Breathe.
最后再推一次 用尽全力推
One last push. One last big push.
对了 加油
That's it. Come on!
戈迪 能跟你说几句吗
Gordy. Could I have a word?
还有杰尼丝
Uh, and-and Janice.
没事的 我一定会没事的
It's okay. It's going to be okay.
整个教区的人都在为我们祈祷
We got the whole parish praying for us.
这周由爸爸照顾你们 所以...
Your dad has you this week, so...
你去打电话给他 告诉他文件在柜子里
you should call him, tell him about the files in the closet.
妈妈...
Mom...?
去告诉他
Just tell him.
一定不会有事的
Nothing's going to happen.
也许吧 不过以防万一...
Maybe not. But just in case...
我爱你
I love you.
前往"探戈酒店"
Proceed to hotel tango.
好了 镇静剂小组听好了
All right, sedation team, listen up.
艾瑞森中士是你们的组长
Sergeant Ericson is your lead.
他会安排休息 今天会是很难熬的一天
He'll monitor breaks. This is gonna be a long day.
工作45分钟后强制休息15分钟 绝对不要忘记你的搭档
Mandatory 15 minutes every 45. Never forget your buddy.
记住 你们不是一个人 你们是两人一体
Remember, you're not one, you're two.
第一个人负责打开笼子
The first person to the cage will open it,
确保没有任何障碍物
making sure that there's no obstruction.
第二个人拿杆子...
The second one will position the pole...
-懂了吗  -懂了
-You got it?  -Yeah.
一旦笼门打开 你就要马上控制住猴子
So that as soon as the door is open you've got it right there
防止猴子逃跑
to prevent any chance of escape.
打完镇静剂的猴子将被送去安乐死
Sedated monkeys will be transported to the euthanizing station.
好了 大家来整理一下桌面
All right, let's clear this up!
我们需要一个整洁的工作台
So, We have a good work surface here!
目前我们对这种病毒所知不多
Now, we don't know a lot about this virus.
它是怎么传播的 如何侵入人体的 都不清楚
How it's spreading in here, how it's ravaging the body.
但我们有样本
But we get samples,
也许下一次 这些猴子就能帮我们阻止病毒的传播了
and maybe these guys will help us stop this thing next time.
也许我们还能找到治疗方法
Maybe we can help us find the cure.
趁猴子的心脏还在跳动的时候 在这里抽取血液样本
We'll take any blood samples here while the heart is still pumping,
然后到那里注射安乐死针剂
and then we'll inject the euthanizing agent over here.
最后送到这里进行解剖
After that, they're taken here for dissection.
工作完成
End of the line.
每只猴子身上要提取至少五份样本
We need up to five samples from each.
每份样本都要标注采自哪只猴子
Each tagged and labeled per monkey.
工作结束后 将尸体进行三层包裹
When we're done, we triple-bag each body.
准备拿去烧毁
Prepare it for incineration.
所有表面都要消毒
We bleach every surface.
先用几加仑消毒剂清洗管道 然后每排出一次污血
Prime the drains with a couple of gallons, then every time blood goes down,
再倒一罐消毒剂
follow it with another jug.
可以注射了
Bring in your syringe pole.
我知道里面已经很危险了 但是相信我
I know it's already hot in here, but trust me:
还会更糟的
It's going to get worse.
所以 把握好自己的节奏
So, pace yourself.
慢慢来...
Easy, easy...
成功
Got it!
我从来没想过 你会是那个在这看表的人
I never knew you to be one to watch the time down here.
杰瑞说他会报个平安的
Jerry said he'd check in.
听着 我相信肯定会没事的
Look, I'm sure everything's fine.
这是雷斯顿送来的第一批 "一批猴子身上的样本"
It's the first batch from Reston, "samples from a dozen monkeys."
我开始觉得卡特说的有道理了
I'm starting to think that Carter had a point.
还有罗德斯说的
So did Rhodes.
这种伊波拉病毒跟之前的有一些非常不同的地方
There's something very different about this Ebola virus.
阳性反应
It glowed.
绝对不可能在猴子身上有这种症状
There's no way this could be happening to these monkeys,
而人体却最多只是发烧
and no human's shown more than a fever.
四例阳性病人伴有头痛 但是没有呕吐 没有出血吗
Four positive cases and headaches, no vomiting, no hemorrhaging?
其他人本来应该生病的
Someone along the way would have gotten sick...
可能是因为潜伏期更长才没有生病
could be that nobody's sick because the incubation time is longer.
在症状出现前会传染给更多人
Spreading to a lot of people before any symptoms appear.
喂 你太累了吧
Hey. You're exhausted.
去吧 我来收拾  好吗
Go. I'll clean up. Okay?
我再待几分钟
I'll just be a few minutes.
好的 谢谢 谢了
Okay. Thank you. Thanks.
我随后就来
I'll be right behind you.
看起来已经不动了
Doesn't look like it's moving much.
嗯 我也觉得它不动了
No. I don't see it moving.
快抓 它要逃跑了
Get it! He's getting away!
萨拉 我们得把这只控制住 我先给他打完针
Sarah, we need to get this one down first. Let me inject it!
不 我们得...
No, We have to...
他妈的为什么要把两只放在一个笼子里
Why the hell did they put two in one cage?
我们得从卡车里再拿点标签出来
We're going to need more tags out of the truck.
快关门
Shut the door!
什么
What?!
往门那儿跑了
Going for the door!
快关门
Shut the door!
上校 有一只逃跑了
Colonel, one escaped!
封锁出口 有一只逃跑了
Cover the exits. We've got a rogue!
收到 长官
Yes, sir.
-你还好吗  -嗯 我没事
Are you all right? -Yeah, yeah, I'm fine.
-奥曼  -什么
- Orman. - What?
这是猴子的还是你的血
Is this from a monkey or is that your blood?
不 这肯定是哪个样本的 或者...
No, it must be from one of the samples or...
封闭前请分流
Routing before air lock.
第二批
Secondary hatch.
彼得
Peter!
醒醒 你得赶紧出去
Wake up, you've got to get out of here.
走吧
Come on.
我不能再失去其他人了 特别是你
I can't lose anyone else go. Especially not you.
-等等 "再失去"是什么意思  -我们刚收到消息
-Wait, anybody else?  -We've got incoming.
雷斯顿那里出事了吗
A breach at Reston?
还不知道
I don't know.
我只知道他们马上会有人过来 而且直接送到隔离室
All I know is they're coming in and they're going to the Slammer.
你还好吗 看着我
You okay? Look at me.
我没事
I'm okay.
都在D区
Both in D gone.
B10 跟紧我
Bravo ten, stick with me.
狄克逊 我们这儿有只猴子跑了
Dixon. We have an escaped monkey.
可能去了通风口
It might be going for the vents.
你上屋顶
Get up on the roof.
收...收到
Uh... c-copy that.
没事了 退后 别乱动
It's all right, get back! Stay still!
我们不能让它跑出去 对面就是住宅 还有个操场
We can't let it out, there's houses across the street and a playground.
威奇托 上屋顶
Wichita, get to the roof!
收到 长官
Yes, sir!
它在逃跑 快跟上
It's on the move! Come on!
手电照天花板
Keep your flashlights to the ceiling!
这东西动作很快
This thing is quick!
快点 注意头上
Come on! Heads up!
如果看到了就大喊
Give out a shout if you see him!
这儿 我看到了
Yeah, I got him!
喂 在哪儿
Hey! Where is it?
我不知道 我只知道有只猴子逃跑了
I don't know. All I know is a monkey escaped.
就在那
It's right there!
看 那儿有个敞开的通风口
Look. There's an open vent.
在这儿
There he is!
我在这儿扎不到它
I can't jab him from here.
它又跑了
He's on the move!
往杆子那儿跑了 西南边
It's headed for the shaft. Southwest side.
在那儿
There!
快快快
Go, go, go!
抓到了吗
You got it!?
屋顶上的可以退后了
Stand down on the roof.
我们抓到了
We got him.
体征尚可
Vitals are okay.
血压升高
Blood pressure is rising.
好 找人去通知一下
All right. And find anyone to notify.
我不知道发生了什么
I don't know what happened.
我一直非常小心
I was being so careful.
没事的 这里的每个人都会照顾你
It's okay. Everyone here's going to look after you.
要21天吗 他们这么说的
21 days? That's what they said.
别那么想 想想现在的事
Can't think like that. Stay present.
这连个杂志都没有
There's not even a magazine.
他们把这里收拾得可干净...
They clean this place up good...
除了我什么都没有
Nothing to off myself with.
我刚才怎么说的 别瞎想
What did I say? Get out of your head.
工厂里是怎么回事
What's going on in the facility?
我一直在想 这个处理猴子的任务
I thought this, this taking out those monkeys,
可能就类似兽医学校里面任务比较重的一天...
it'd be like a hard day at vet school...
但是它们的眼睛...
But their eyes...
就好像盯着人类的眼睛一样...
it is like looking into another person...
眼神是疯的
It's crazy in there.
阴暗的
Dark.
取暖设备坏了 每个人都累死了
Heat is all whacked out. Everyone is exhausted.
简直一团乱
It's messed up.
听我说 凯尔
Listen to me, Kyle.
我每天都会过来 检查你的情况
I'm going to come back and check up on you every day,
但是如果一旦觉得难以忍受了
but if it gets unbearable in there,
我需要你深呼吸
I need you to breathe through it.
就像我教你的那样 好吗
Like I taught you. Okay?
深呼吸
Just breathe through it.
我会回来的
I'll be back.
91探戈队 我是贾克斯上校
91-Tango Unit. This is Colonel Jaax.
嗨 听到你的声音真好
Hi. It's good to hear your voice.
我们进来的时候晚了
We were late going in.
听说了 听着 杰瑞...
I heard. Listen, Jerry...
我测试了其余工人的血样
I tested the rest of the workers' blood.
有两个新病例
We've got two new cases.
好吧...
Okay...
好吧 我们猜到了 不是吗
well, uh, that's not unexpected is it?
是的
No.
但我们不知道有谁直接接触了体液 所以...
But we just don't know who had direct exposure through fluids so...
好吧 我们会小心的 谢谢提醒
Okay, we'll be careful. Thanks for the heads up.
我 我得进去了
I, uh, I got to get in there.
杰瑞 你还好吗
Hey, Jerry. You okay?
嗯 我没事 我得挂了
Yeah, I'm fine. I, uh, I gotta go.
长官
Sir?
请求加入雷斯顿团队
Permission to join the team in Reston.
我以为你和上校已经谈过了 南希
Thought you and the Colonel had already been through this, Nancy.
是的 长官 但他没在这儿
Yes, sir, but he isn't here.
91探戈队超常发挥 但他们需要帮助
91-Tangos are outperforming expectations but they need relief.
杰瑞的一位关键队员现在进了隔离室
One of Jerry's key team members is now in the Slammer.
就像您自己说的 卡特是我的责任
And as you said so yourself, Carter is my charge.
我得进去看着他才行
Only right that I'd be in there to watch him.
你发烧多久了
How long have you had a fever?
就一两天
Just a day or two,
但是我孩子学校里有流感 所以...
but there's a flu going around my kid's school, so...
好吧 现在是流感季 所以...
Yeah, well, it's flu season, so...
你呢 感觉怎么样
What about you? How you feeling?
我不知道
I don't know.
感觉他们一直在把空调调低
It kind of feels like they keep turning on the A/C down here.
我们的测试 显示是...
I mean, our tests, they came back...
是的 阴性的...
Yeah, they're negative but...
但这玩意儿行为不同
this thing's acting different.
它...
I mean, it's...
症状出现得很慢
it's slow to show symptoms.
我不知道...
I don't know...
感觉我要崩溃了
Feel like I am going to crack up.
不知道我妈妈是怎么做到了
I don't know how my mom did it.
她发现自己得了癌症
She found out she had cancer.
知道毫无希望
She knew there was no hope.
知道了多久呢
Knew it for what?
八 九个月
Eight, ten months.
而我们才多久呢 两天多一点
And for us it's been, what? A little over two days.
我觉得是因为我们被困在这儿 但是...
I think it's 'cause we're locked down here, but...
我的思想变得很黑暗 哥们
my thoughts have been getting pretty dark, man.
我是科学家 应该知道这样不对 但是...
I mean, I'm a scientist, I should know better but...
你觉得人们生病的时候会知道吗
do you think people know when they're sick?
就 内心深处
You know, like, deep down?
在某种程度上
On some level?
不知道 也许是身体的某种行为
I don't know, maybe it's something the body does.
让你做好准备 这样 等医生走进来说
Kind of prepares you, so when the doctor walks in and he says,
"知道吗 一切都结束了" 你不会完全惊慌失措
"You know, it's all over," you don't totally freak out.
因为某种程度上
Because on some level,
你内心已经知道了真相
you already know the truth.
我不知道该相信什么
I don't know what to believe.
我最大的儿子 他 他想开始打篮球
My oldest, he, um, he wants to start basketball.
我整个高中都在打篮球
I played all throughout high school.
我爸从没错过一场比赛
My dad never missed a game.
我就不该让你闻的
I never should've made you smell it.
你又没有逼我
You didn't make me.
本 如果发生了什么...
Ben, if anything happens...
我非常抱歉
I'm so sorry.
我知道
I know.
还有没有其他血样像这个一样 看起来像浓汤
Any of the other have been all soup, like this guy?
我没看到过 更像是糊不是汤
Not that I've seen. More mush than soup.
这是哪个房间的
What cell is it from?
K室 怎么了
Cell K. Why?
把这些样本打包 然后继续
Bag those samples and move on.
你要走了吗
You're leaving?
我得去检查一个东西
I got to check something.
接手吧 你会没事的
Take over, you'll be fine.
好了 这是你的第三块电池 长官
Okay. That's your third battery, sir.
长官 我们已经行动了12个小时
Sir, we've been going at this for 12 hours.
其他人每45分钟就会休息...
Rest of us have been breaking every 45 minutes...
你也需要休息一下
You need one, too.
我越早弄完
The faster I get through these
我们需要处理的感染动物就越少
the fewer infected animals we're handling.
但你说得对 我们在这儿待得太久了
But you're right. We have been in here too long.
让大家出去吃点东西 把这衣服脱了
Have everybody get some food. Get them out of their suits.
是 长官 但如果你要留下 我也留下
Yes, sir, but if you're staying, I'm staying.
我不会让你独自留下来
I'm not leaving you here alone.
91探戈队注意了...
Attention 91-Tangos...
告诉你阿姨
Well, just tell your aunt to put the
把烤箱调到275度 直到芝士冒泡...
oven at 275 un-until the cheese bubbles over...
我知道 所以才给你们做了
I know, that's why I made it for you.
还有 转告你哥哥 记得练钢琴 我爱他...
Oh, and tell your brother, um, to practice the piano and that I love him...
我也爱你 好了 亲爱的 拜拜
And I love you too. Okay, honey. Bye.
他们有这种烤嫩鸡...
And they got this barbecue chicken tender thing...
特别好吃
so good.
我们应该去吃点
We should grab a bite.
对吧 上校
Right, Colonel?
杰瑞
Jerry!
上校倒下了 上校倒下了
Colonel down! Colonel down!
上校
Colonel?
还有意识 在呼吸
Still conscious, breathing.
没时间去污了 把车准备好 我们要把他推出去
No time to decon. Get a van ready. We're crashing him out.
确认 已派出医疗运送
Affirmative, med vac en route.
上校
Colonel?
怎么了 有人 有人受伤了吗
What's going on? Is someone, someone injured?
上校倒下了 长官
Colonel's gone down, Ma'am.